里克  里克
Rick, Rick.
好久不见啊  里克
Long time, Rick.
老天啊
Good gracious.
理查德  你好苍白
Richard, you look positively ghastly.
你也早啊  老妈
Good morning to you, too, mother.
不不  我是作为担心的母亲这样说
No, no, no. I'm speaking as a concerned mother.
你真不是病了吗
Are you sure you're not coming down with anything?
没有啊  感觉棒棒的
Not at all. Never better.
那好  那我的任务完成了
Well, good. Then my work here is done.
我要去看些开放住宅了
I'm off to see some open houses.
希望能找到称心如愿的公寓  再见了
Hopefully to find the apartment of my dreams. Ta!
再见
Bye.
-再见  -再见
- Ta! - Bye.
谢谢
Ah, thank you.
阿丽克西斯也走了吗
Is Alexis gone, too?
嗯  她早上有课
Yeah. She had an early-morning class.
你昨晚又睡得不安稳
So, you were restless again last night.
怎么回事
What's going on?
没什么啊
Nothing.
亲爱的  你总那么说  但情况却越来越糟
Babe, you keep saying that, and it keeps getting worse.
你在睡梦中幽咽
You were whimpering in your sleep.
这一周每晚都如此
It's been every night for a week.
说吧  告诉我
So, come on. Talk to me.
就是个梦
It's just a dream.
那么这梦你一直做喽
So it's a recurring dream?
好吧  内容是什么
Okay. About what?
好像是我失踪期间的事
About when I went missing, I think.
那你为什么不跟我说呢
And so why didn't you want to tell me about it?
大概是因为我不想小题大做吧
Probably because I didn't want to make a big deal of it.
但这不是小题  你失去了生命中的两个月
But it is a big deal. You lost two months of your life.
如今又开始梦到
And you're dreaming about it now?
-我觉得你不该无视  -我觉得应该
- I don't think you should ignore this. - I do.
拜托  现在一切都很完美
Come on. Everything is perfect right now.
我们很快乐  其他人也是
You and I are in a great place. Everyone else is.
何必再去深究呢
I mean, why go turning over stones
这些梦可能渐渐就停止了
when the dreams will just probably just go away?
但是并没有停止啊  而且越来越糟
Except they haven't gone away. They're just getting worse.
看你啊  你压力很大
Look at you. You're stressed-out.
精疲力竭
You're exhausted.
你一周都一个字没写了
You haven't written a word in a week.
至少考虑去看医生吧
Look, a-at least consider seeing someone.
我认识可能能帮到你的人
I know somebody who may be able to help.
以前进行过心理治疗吗  卡塞尔先生
Have you ever sought therapy before, Mr. Castle?
如果你见过我母亲
Well, if you'd met my mother,
你就会知道答案是肯定的
you'd know the answer would be yes,
但我生来不喜欢反省
but, uh, by my nature, I try to avoid introspection.
那我们开始吧
Well, let's get started.
能跟我说说你失忆的时期吗
What can you tell me about your missing time?
没多少好说的
Not much.
我记得的最后一件事  是开车去婚礼
The last thing I remember, I was driving to my wedding.
一辆黑SUV开始追车
A black S.U.V. started chasing me.
我被逼冲下了路
Then I was forced off the road.
两个月后
Two months later,
他们在大西洋上发现了我
they found me in the middle of the Atlantic Ocean.
我得过登革热
I had been exposed to dengue fever.
我身上有弹痕  但完全不记得怎么回事
I had a bullet scar with no recollection how I got it,
我什么都不记得
no memory of anything.
我找到了一个叫詹金斯的人
I tracked down a man named Jenkins,
他不知为何与这事有关
who was involved somehow.
他
He, uh...
他说我之所以想不起来
He told me the reason I couldn't remember.
你说过你不想记得
And you said you didn't want to remember.
我们竭尽全力确保你不记得
We went to great lengths to make sure that you didn't.
那么你还是不想记起来吗
And is it still the case that you don't want to remember?
不
No.
我也试图将这事遗忘
I-I've tried to put it behind me,
但这事让我无法释怀
but it haunts me.
每一天我都在想  我去了哪  看到了什么
Not a day goes by I don't wonder where I was, what I saw...
做了什么
what I did.
我的记忆是不是在恢复了
Is it possible my memories are coming back?
梦境有时候的确是记忆
Well, dreams can be memories.
但更多时候只是象征性的
But more often they're symbolic...
是一个问题的隐喻性表达
Metaphoric expressions of an issue or problem.
而且你是个作家  很有创作性
You're also a writer... a creative person.
这或许是你的大脑在建立一套
This could mean your mind is building a narrative
填补这两个月空白的理论
to fill a two-month void.
我也想理解这些梦境
I want to understand these dreams...
他们的含义  他们是否是真的
What they mean and, uh... if they're real.
可以让你进入放松状态
Well, we could put you in a relaxed state,
回顾那段经历
try to revisit the experience.
催眠吗
Hypnosis?
如果你想记笔记  你有笔和纸
You have a pen and paper if you wish to take notes.
你随时可以睁眼  醒来
You may open your eyes and awaken at any time.
可以开始了吗  卡塞尔先生
Are you ready to begin, Mr. Castle?
是的
Yeah.
回顾你能记得的梦境中第一个画面
Go back to the first image you can recall of your dream.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
我睡在一艘船上
I'm asleep on a boat.
在大海里
On the ocean.
好久不见啊  里克
Long time, Rick.
有个人  他跟我打招呼
There's a man there. He says hi to me.
好久不见啊  里克
Long time, Rick.
他认识我
He knows me.
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
他很眼熟  但我说不上是谁
He's familiar, but I-I can't...place him.
这很有效啊
This really works.
好了  这个很眼熟
Okay, there's something familiar.
一个奖杯
A trophy.
比赛的奖杯吗
For some kind of sport?
或许吧  我分辨不出来
Maybe. I-I can't tell.
有人开枪
Now someone's firing a pistol.
我看到了血
I see blood.
地上有个人
There's a man on the floor.
他中枪了  他要死了
He's been shot. He's dying.
我也在
I'm there, too.
我化了迷彩妆
I'm wearing camouflage paint.
我想帮他
I'm trying to help him, but...
你能看到自己的位置吗
Can you see where you are right now?
在一个仓库
In a storage shed.
但一切东西都在动
But it seems like everything is moving.
我在一辆卡车里
I'm in a truck.
我们在丛林里
We're in the jungle.
有人在追我们
And there's someone chasing us.
他们在冲我们开枪
They're shooting at us.
卡车上有个金发的男人
There's a blond man in a truck.
他在带领他们
He's leading the charge.
再快点
Faster!
-军用卡车吗  -不  是民用的
- A military truck? - No, it's a civilian truck.
但有很
But it has a very...
奇怪的
...strange...
车牌
...license plate.
你看到了查克·诺里斯
So the man you saw was Chuck Norris?
不  他不是
No, he wasn't...
查克·诺里斯  当然不会
...Chuck Norris. Of course not.
那就太荒唐
I mean, that would be ridiculous and...
也太酷了
Super-duper cool.
不是  他看上去像查克·诺里斯
But, no. He... he looked like Chuck Norris.
第一次会面颇有成效啊
Well, this was a very productive first session,
卡塞尔先生  不过时间到了
Mr. Castle, but I'm afraid our time is up.
好的  谢谢
Of course. Thank you.
博克医生  我
Uh, Dr. Burke, can I, uh...
明天能再见你吗
Can I see you again tomorrow?
我看看日程吧  但我希望你
Well, I'll check, but I want you to think
能好好想想梦境的含义
about the underlying meaning of the dream.
别把梦境当成真实的记忆
Now, don't assume that the images are actual memories.
告诉你们
I'm telling you, guys.
我毫不怀疑  那就是我真实的记忆
There's no doubt in my mind. They are actual memories.
尽管博克医生说可能不是的
Even though Dr. Burke said they might not be?
那是我们第一次会面
It...was our first session.
他只是保守  但感觉好真实
He was just being cautious. But they felt real.
因为那就是真实的
Because they... they are real.
那么你跟查克·诺里斯在丛林里跟人械斗吗
So you were in jungle combat? With Chuck Norris.
就像《杀出火地狱》那样吗
Like "Missing in action"?
他拍的那部在越南营救战俘的电影吗
The movie he did about rescuing P.O.W.s from vietnam?
但那不是查克·诺里斯  也不是电影
Uh, only it wasn't Chuck Norris, it wasn't a movie,
-我也不在越南  -这是没错
- and I wasn't in Vietnam. - You got that right.
因为托瑞正在查的车牌
Because the license plate that tory is checking on...
就是我看到的那个  上面有阿拉伯字母
the one I saw... it had Arabic characters.
说阿拉伯语有丛林的国家
Okay, so an Arabic-speaking country with a jungle?
也门  索马里
Um...Yemen... Somalia.
嗯  差不多
Yeah, I guess so.
等我们找到和查克·诺里斯长得像的那个人
We'll know more when we track down
就能知道更多了
that Chuck Norris look-alike.
你打算怎么找呢
How do you plan on doing that?
我跟你们说的那个军队骷髅纹身
That military skull tattoo I told you about.
可以利用纹身确认他  对吧
That could help I.D. him, right?
我们尽力去查吧
We'll see what we can find out.
不过希望不是很大
But it's a long shot at best.
我知道这似乎是不可能的
I know this seems impossible.
我们很多案子一开始都是这样
A lot of our cases do at first.
现在有了些线索  卡塞尔
There's something there, Castle,
所以我们就顺着线索查  看看会有什么结果
so we'll just follow it and see where it leads.
我查到一些车牌的情况
I got something on that license plate.
原来那些不是阿拉伯语
It turns out, this isn't Arabic.
是泰文的字母
These are letters in the Thai alphabet.
什么意思
What does it mean?
车牌的注册地是清迈
That the license plate was registered in Chiang Mai,
泰国北部的一个省
a province in northern Thailand.
我去了泰国
I was in Thailand,
跟查克·诺里斯一起被人追杀吗
getting shot at with Chuck Norris?
凯特
Kate?
凯特  你醒了吗
Kate, are you awake?
阿丽克西斯
Alexis, hey.
怎么  怎么了
What's -- what's wrong?
抱歉  我有个考试
Sorry. I have an exam,
但爸爸这样子我不能直接走掉
but I didn't want to leave dad like this.
他研究泰国那事太专注了
He's kind of gone off the deep end about thailand.
你一晚都没睡吗
Hey. Were you up all night?
我在研究在我失踪期间
I'm researching armed conflicts
发生在泰国北部的武装冲突
in northern Thailand during the time I was missing.
我肯定是卷入到其中了
Somehow, I must have been part of one of them.
你发现什么了吗
You find anything?
没有  还没有  不过会发现的
No, not yet. But I will.
你想不想休息一会儿  吃点早餐
You want to take a break, maybe get some breakfast?
不了  想出来再吃
No, not until I figure this out.
我去过那儿  凯特  我去过
I was there, Kate. I was there.
我中枪了  所以我才有枪疤
I was shot at, which explains my bullet scar.
我还得了登革热
I was exposed to dengue fever,
而那里正是这种病盛行的地方
a disease that's prevalent in the region.
所有事都对上了
Everything fits.
可是卡塞尔  你为什么会在婚礼当天被绑架
But, Castle, why would you be abducted on our wedding day
然后去了泰国呢
and end up in Thailand?
史上最差的单身派对了吧
Worst bachelor party ever?
或许博克医生说得对
You know, maybe Dr. Burke is right.
你在梦里见到的那些场景
Maybe those images that you saw in your dream
或许不是你真正的记忆
are not really your memories.
不  真的是我的记忆  真的
Oh, no. They're memories. They're memories.
而且你说了要跟着它们走
And you said follow them wherever they go,
这就是它所走的方向  泰国
and this is where they go -- Thailand.
这一切都跟泰国有关
This is all about thailand.
好吧  我们先不考虑泰国
Okay, well, why don't we take a step back from Thailand.
想想别的方面
Why don't we take a look at some of the other images,
比如  奖杯
Like the -- the trophy.
跟奖杯没关
The trophy's irrelevant.
它能出现在你的梦里就是有原因的
Well, it was in your dream for a reason.
你说好像在哪见过
You said it was familiar in what way?
是什么样的
What did it look like?
很便宜的那种  奖给小孩子的
Cheap. You know, something that you would give a child.
好的  会不会是阿丽克西斯得的什么奖
Okay. So could it have been an award that Alexis won?
又或许是你得的
Maybe something that you won?
写作得的奖
Something for writing?
我知道是什么了
I know what it is.
就是这个
This is it.
就是这个奖杯  这就是...
This is the trophy. This is...
我是在菲克罗夫特预科学校
I, I won this in a -- in a debate competition
参加辩论赛赢的
back at Faircroft prep.
为什么会出现在你的梦里呢
Why would that be in your dream?
不知道  不过
I don't know, but...
等等
Wait a minute.
菲利普·巴莱特
Phillip Bartlett.
菲利普·巴莱特是谁
Who's Phillip Bartlett?
菲利普·巴莱特和我  共同获得了第一
Phillip Bartlett and I, we tied for first place.
我们都得到了这个奖杯
We shared this trophy.
我梦里的那个人
That man in my dream,
跟我打招呼的那个人  就是他
the one who says hello, it was him.
他也到我这个年龄了  不过
I mean, he's my age now, but...
菲利普·巴莱特
Phillip Bartlett.
好久不见啊  里克
Long time, Rick.
他跟这事有关
He's a part of this.
我来找他
If I'm gonna track him down,
你去调查一下他的背景
I'm gonna need you to do a background check on him.
好吧  现在除了查克·诺里斯
Okay, so now it's Chuck Norris
又加上高中的老同学了吗
and some old buddy from high school?
拜托  我只是让你们去查一下菲利普·巴莱特
Come on, guys. I'm just asking you to run Phillip Bartlett.
卡塞尔一定要弄清楚是怎么回事
Look, Castle needs to know what's going on.
如果什么都查不到呢
What if these leads go nowhere?
那他也要知道结果
Then he needs to know that, as well.
抱歉  托瑞
Excuse me. Tory!
那个车牌还有什么新线索吗
Hey, any more news on that license plate?
一点点  注册那个车牌的公司
A little -- the plate was registered
是一家泰国的货运公司  1987年倒闭了
to a Thai freight company that went out of business in 1987.
1987年
1987?
卡塞尔怎么会在将近三十年后
How would Castle see it on a truck
看到挂这牌的车呢
almost 30 years later?
我不知道
I don't know.
有可能那个车牌被偷了  或者
It's possible the plate was stolen, or...
或者什么
Or what?
我对那个车牌进行了图像搜索
I ran an image search of the plate.
在很多动作电影的追车场景中
Similar license plates appeared in several action films,
都出现过这种相似的车牌
during car-chase sequences.
这么说你认为他是在电影里看见的
So you think he might have seen it in a film.
有可能
Maybe.
玛莎  怎么了
Martha. Hey. What's -- what's going on?
理查德简直走火入魔了
Richard is completely obsessed,
我很担心他
and I am concerned about him.
我知道  我也是
I know. Me too.
他从来没跟我说过失忆的事
He never spoke to me about the missing time.
我以为那事都过去了  你呢
I thought he was at peace with it. Didn't you?
我想是他的梦让他意识到
Well, I guess the dreams made him realize
那件事还没过去
that he wasn't at peace.
他想要忘记那两个月
He chose to forget those two months.
他做出这种选择  一定有个好理由
He must have had a very good reason for wanting to do that.
我觉得不应该继续追查这件事
I think looking into this is a bad idea.
玛莎  我觉得这由不得他
Martha, I-I don't think that this is a choice for him.
我想他必须要知道真相
I think that he needs to know the truth.
如果他找不出真相怎么办
What if he never finds out the truth?
如果他查不到什么怎么办
What if he never learns anything?
或者更糟糕的是  他查到了不好的事怎么办
Or worse, what if he finds out something awful?
我会陪着他的  无论怎样
I'll be with him. Wherever this leads.
而且我向你保证  我不会让他走太远
And I promise you I am not gonna let him go too far.
-谢谢你  -没事
- Thank you. - Yeah.
好久不见啊  里克
Long time, Rick.
菲尔·巴莱特  谢谢你能来
Phil Bartlett. Thank you for coming.
我知道你来找我
Well, I knew it was only a matter of time
是迟早的事
before I'd hear from you.
你知道我会找你
You were expecting my call?
当然了  而且我会帮你的
Of course I was. And I'm -- I'm here for you.
谢天谢地  太好了
Oh, thank God. What a relief. Okay.
我要跟你谈谈泰国的事
I need to talk to you about Thailand.
泰国的事你都知道些什么
What do you know about Thailand?
我去过那儿  见过你
I was there. I saw you.
你不应该知道的
You're not supposed to know.
谁都不应该知道  而且你不能告诉别人
Nobody is. And you can't tell anyone.
我不会的  不会的  我保证
I won't. I won't. I promise.
不过你要告诉我你在那儿所看到的事
As long as you tell me your version of what happened.
我不能说
I can't do that.
我要知道你所知道的
I need to know what you know.
我说的这些话绝对不能外传
What I'm about to say can never be repeated.
明白
Understood.
我去泰国是参加一个投资会议
I was in Thailand to attend an investment conference.
我们去了一家曼谷的夜店
We hit this Bangkok nightclub.
她太漂亮了
Oh, she was so beautiful.
我对天发誓  我以为她是个女的
I thought she was a woman. I swear to god.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
不对  我让你说清迈的事
No. I need you to tell me about Chiang Mai.
我没去过清迈
I was never in Chiang Mai.
我是在曼谷  你说你看见我了
I was in Bangkok. You said you saw me?
是的  不过  我没看见你那个
Yeah, but -- no, I-I didn't see that.
我想我们还是别再说这件事了
I think it's best that we never speak of this again.
等等  你当时在那儿  我看见你了
Wait, no. No. You were there. I know you were.
听着  我不知道你在玩什么把戏
Look, I don't know what kind of game you're playing here --
这不是把戏
It's not a game.
我看到我们的奖杯  我们为辩论社赢来的
I-I saw our trophy -- the one we won for debate club.
你说你在等我找你
You were expecting my call.
你为什么认为我会找上你
Why would you be expecting my call?
菲利普·巴莱特
Phillip Bartlett --
巴莱特-布拉多克财富管理公司
Bartlett-Braddock wealth management.
我想让你成为我的客户
I wanted to take you on as a client.
现在来看  还是算了吧
Now not so much.
你知道吗  我从来都不是什么辩论高手
You know, for the record, I was never a debate geek, all right?
我是打曲棍球的
I played lacrosse.
这说不通
It doesn't make any sense.
他肯定与这有关  他在我梦里出现过
He has to be part of this. He was in the dream.
但我们已经查过他了
Except we checked him out.
第一次也是唯一一次
The first and only time
菲利普·巴莱特去泰国是一个月前
Phillip Bartlett traveled to Thailand was a month ago,
没有任何线索能把他和这件事联系起来
and there's nothing that connects him to all of this.
我甚至打给了菲克罗夫特预备学校
I even called Faircroft Prep.
他们确定菲利普·巴莱特没参加过辩论小组
They confirmed Phillip Bartlett was not on the debate team.
我也没有和人并列第一过
I didn't share first place with anyone.
宝贝  也许你太把你的梦当真了
Uh, babe, maybe you're taking this whole dream thing too literally.
或者也许是你把两段记忆结合在了一起
Or maybe you've combined two memories together.
不  我没有编故事
No. I'm not making this up.
但万一
But what if...
但万一这是《全面回忆》的状况呢
What if this is "Total recall"?
他们不仅仅消除了我的记忆
Not only did they erase my memories,
还用虚构的记忆把之前的替换掉了吗
but they replaced them with false memories?
但即使是虚构的记忆
But the false memories
也应该是基于现实的  对吗
would have to be based in reality, right?
否则  菲利普·巴莱特怎么会在其中呢
Otherwise, why would Phillip Bartlett be in them?
卡塞尔  听我说
Uh, Castle, listen to me --
贝克特探长  过来说句话
Detective Beckett? A word?
我注意到你动用了资源
I've noticed you've devoted resources
对菲利普·巴莱特进行了背景调查
to running a background check on Phillip Bartlett.
还追查了泰国的汽车牌照吗
And tracing license plates in Thailand?
长官  我在跟踪
Uh, sir, I was following up
一些关于卡塞尔失踪的新线索
on some new leads about Castle's disappearance.
和查克·诺里斯有关吗
In connection to Chuck Norris?
是的  有点复杂
Yeah. It's complicated.
凯特  我知道这对他来说很重要
Kate, I know how important this is to him.
但这些线索可靠吗
But these leads, are they solid?
或者只是卡塞尔先生想做最后的挣扎
Or is Mr. Castle just grasping at straws?
我调查了一下那个纹身
I dug into that tattoo.
那个标记代表着三角洲特种部队  对吗
That insignia -- that means delta force, right?
是的  这也是查克·诺里斯的电影名字
Yeah. It's also the title of a Chuck Norris movie.
三角洲那帮人不宣扬自己
Well, delta guys don't advertise,
所以  纹身的人现在肯定没有在服役
so whoever's wearing that ink is no longer active duty.
旗帜表明
It says here on the banner
他是第75游骑兵团
that he's out of the 75th Ranger Regiment,
三营B连的
3rd Battalion, B company.
我向五角大楼的兄弟确认了
Now, I checked with my boy at the Pentagon,
曾经服役过的人中只有很少一部分人
and there's only a handful of guys with that service history
和你说见过的人相匹配
who match the guy you said you saw.
给你
Here you go.
谢谢你  埃斯波西托  真是太好了
Thank you for this, Esposito. This is great.
他肯定会在里头
So, he will be in here somewhere.
但他没有
Yeah, but he's not.
这里没有一个人长得像查克·诺里斯
None of those guys look like Chuck Norris.
你不相信我  对吗
You don't believe me, do you?
在我看来  你失踪两个月里发生的故事
For my money, your story about the missing two months
一点都不符合常理
never added up.
现在看来也是
It still doesn't.
这就是那个人
This is the guy.
-算了  卡塞尔  -就是这个人
- Come on, Castle. - No, this is the guy.
这人一点都不像查克·诺里斯
That guy looks nothing like Chuck Norris.
有胡子的话就像了
He would with a beard.
而且他就生活在纽约市
And he lives right here in the city.
他叫杰夫·鲍尔斯  2009年光荣退伍
His name is Jeff Powers -- honorable discharge in 2009,
之后在伊拉克和阿富汗做承包商
then he worked as a contractor in Iraq and Afghanistan.
一看就是那种
This is just the kind of guy
会在泰国当雇佣兵的人
who could be a mercenary in Thailand.
他在那儿  贝克特  他知道发生了什么
He was there, Beckett. He knows what happened.
希望如此  但如果他不知道
I hope so, but if he doesn't,
我们就得先缓缓
then we need to take a breath
讨论怎么追查下去
and discuss how to pursue this.
或者是否要追查下去
Or whether to pursue it.
没有必要
That won't be necessary.
所有的答案都在这门后
All the answers are right behind this door.
卡塞尔  你在做什么
Castle! What are you doing?
没关系  他认识我
It's okay. He knows me.
杰夫·鲍尔斯
Jeff Powers?
是来自泰国的里克·卡塞尔
It's Rick Castle from Thailand.
你的门没锁
Your door was unlocked.
只是想问你几个问题
Just wanted to ask you a few questions.
卡塞尔
Castle.
就是他
That's him.
那是在我梦里的出现的人
That's the guy in my dream.
好吧  不用说
Well, needless to say,
头上的枪伤很可能就是死因
that G.S.W. to the head is the likely cause of death.
什么时候发生的
When did this happen?
根据肝脏温度来看  大约在昨晚午夜
Based on liver temp, about midnight last night.
但全面的尸检后  我会知道更多信息
But I'll know more once I do a full work-up on him.
卡塞尔开始想起了这个人
Castle starts remembering this guy.
突然之间  他就被人杀了
And all of a sudden, he becomes a homicide victim?
有点奇怪
That's kind of weird.
是的  不仅仅是奇怪  这很可疑
Yeah. It's not just weird. It's suspicious.
我希望卡塞尔的故事是真的
Well, I was hoping to prove Castle's story was true,
但并不是像这样
but not like this.
是啊  联系一下他的亲属
Yeah. Contact the next-of-kin.
让我们查明杰夫·鲍尔斯卷入了什么
Let's find out what Jeff Powers was into.
说来容易做起来难
Easier said than done.
他的父母双亡  没有妻子和兄弟姐妹
His parents are dead, no wife or siblings.
希望能找到某个他的朋友或者战友
Hoping to track down a friend or someone he served with.
我已经在查了
But I'm on it.
你怎么样
Hey. How you doing?
乐观地说  至少我没有疯
On the bright side, at least I'm not crazy.
我从没认为你发疯了
Yeah, well, I never thought you were.
我曾一度认为我疯了
Well, I sure thought I was.
你肯定也有怀疑过
You must have had a few moments of doubt.
我们知道是谁杀了他吗
Do we have any idea who killed him?
现在还为时过早
It's too soon to tell.
但我们会追查到底的
But we're gonna get to the bottom of this.
万一这是我的过错怎么办
What if it's my fault?
万一是我的调查害他被杀了怎么办
What if me poking around is what got him killed?
卡塞尔  怎么可能呢
Castle, how could that even be possible?
我不知道  也许我被人跟踪或监视了
I don't know. Maybe I'm being followed or watched.
他的死肯定不是巧合
His death cannot be a coincidence.
看上去也不像  是吗
Yeah. It doesn't seem like one, does it?
20分钟后我可能会知道得更多
Well, I may know more in 20 minutes.
你是说你和博克医生的预约吗
You mean your appointment with Dr. Burke?
是的  如果我能记起在泰国的事情
Yeah, if I can remember about Thailand,
也许能帮我们解决这个案子
it may help us solve this murder.
好的  和我保持联系
Okay. Keep me close.
会的
Always.
贝克特
Hey, uh, Beckett?
请务必告诉我有线索了
Hey. Please tell me we got something.
我找到了这个
Well, I did find this --
一张活色生香的鸡尾酒餐巾纸
a cocktail napkin from Exotica.
是个脱衣舞俱乐部吗
I take it that's a strip club?
是的  这个在被害人的口袋里
Yeah. And this was in the victim's pocket.
昨晚回到家遇害之前
It could be where he was last night
他有可能就在那
before he came home and wound up dead.
有可能他在那遇到了凶手
And it might be where he met our killer.
我看看是否能找到这个俱乐部
I'll see if I can find out who he spent time with
和他在一起的人
at, uh, exotica.
我当然认识杰夫  他是常客
Sure, I know Jeff. He's a regular.
他一周会来几次
He's at the club a few nights a week.
他很好  一直都很绅士
He's nice, always a gentleman.
他昨晚在那  是吗
Fact is, he was there last night, right?
他当时和别人在一起吗
Was he there with somebody?
只有我
Just me.
安珀  你注意到他和其他人说过话
Amber, did you notice if he talked to anyone,
或者和别人一起走了吗
or left with anyone?
杰夫不是对社交感兴趣的人
Jeff wasn't much for socializing.
他有没有你知道的朋友
Did he have any friends that you know of?
去俱乐部找过他的人
Anybody ever stop by the club?
有一个朋友
Yeah. One friend did.
-谁  -军队里的人
- Who? - Some army buddy.
他来找杰夫
He came in looking for Jeff.
他来城里  想要给他个惊喜
He was in town, visiting, and wanted to surprise him,
所以让我不要说出去
So he made me swear not to say anything.
什么时候的事
When was this?
三天前吧
Three days ago, maybe?
安珀  这个杰夫的战友
Amber, this army buddy of Jeff's --
你对他的印象清晰吗  能帮我们
Do you think you remember this guy well enough
做张素描吗
to help us out with a sketch?
可以吧
Sure.
为什么  杰夫出事了吗
Why? Is something going on with Jeff?
没有用
It's not working.
我想不起什么新线索了
I-I-I can't remember anything new.
只能想起之前的图像
I keep coming up with the same images.
我们换个方式思考吧
Let's look at this another way.
也许你想起了那些图像是有原因的
Perhaps the images came to you for a reason.
-有什么事触发了记忆  -什么事呢
- Something trigred them. - Like what?
你一周前开始做这梦
You began having this dream over a week ago.
一周前发生了什么不寻常的事吗
Did anything unusual occur on that particular day?
没啊  我起床  和贝克特吃了早餐
No. I got up. I had breakfast with Beckett.
她要去法院所以我去了健身房
She had to go to court. Uh, I went to the gym.
之后呢
And then?
写了会儿小说
I wrote for a while.
我想换个环境
I wanted a change of scenery,
所以带着笔记本电脑去了咖啡店
so I took my laptop to the coffee shop...
你想起什么了
There. What did you just remember?
只是在咖啡店时
Just that when I was at the coffee shop,
突然听到种奇怪的
I-I got this strange, um,
像是耳鸣似的嗡响
like a buzzing, ringing in my ears.
回想一周前你在咖啡店的经历
Let's go back a week ago to the coffee shop.
这种嗡响出现时你在干什么
What were you doing when this buzzing first started?
写小说
I was writing.
或者说  卡住了写不出来
Or, rather, procrastinating.
我卡在一个场景上  于是开始观察周围的人
I was stuck on a scene, so I was just people-watching.
看到认识的人了吗
Anyone you knew?
或者认出了谁
Or recognized?
没有
No.
我想不是
No, I don't think so.
等等  那声音
Wait a minute. That ringing --
是在我看到电视时响起的
It started when I looked up at the TV.
当时是什么节目
What was playing?
当地新闻
Something from the local news.
还有两天就是4.15了
April 15th is only two days away.
你当时看见的应该是这段
This is the clip you would have seen.
好的一面是
But, on the bright side,
邮局将延迟关门
Many post offices will be open extra late
为了那些临时申报者能及时上交纳税申报单
To accept tax returns from last-minute filers.
不过是条纳税申报的新闻
It's just some report on tax day.
也许嗡鸣声和这无关
Maybe the buzzing has nothing to do with this.
再看一下吧
Just keep watching.
也许还有别的什么
There's got to be something else there.
联邦大厦  教堂街
The federal plaza, church street,
还有唐人街的邮局都将延长服务时间
and chinatown post offices will all have extended hours
等等  暂停一下  暂停
Wait. Um, pause it. Pause it.
当然了  税务局
Of course, the I.R.S. --
怎么了
What is it?
托瑞  放大一下那个人
Tory, zoom in on that man right there.
我见过他
I know him.
他就是坐车追我们的其中一个人
He was the one chasing us in the truck.
-你确定吗  -我确定  他也在泰国
- Are you sure? - Yes, I'm sure. He was in Thailand.
拿到去脱衣舞俱乐部
We got our sketch back of the guy who showed up
找杰夫·鲍尔斯那人的画像了
at the strip club, asking for Jeff Powers.
同一个人
The same man.
先是在泰国  现在又在纽约
First in Thailand, now in New York.
不管他是谁  这事肯定与他有关
Whoever he is, he's at the center of this.
我想起来了这些
Catching a glimpse of his face
都是因为看到了他
is what started all this.
是他触发了我的那些梦  但他是谁呢
It's what triggered my dreams. But who is he?
关于他你还记得什么别的吗
What else do you remember about him?
他当时穿得像个大兵
Uh, he was dressed like a soldier.
你说他在向手下吼着什么
You said he was yelling at his men?
用的什么语言
In what language?
快点  开快点
Faster! Faster!
他说英语
He was speaking English.
他是美国人吗  还是英国人
So, was he American? British?
不  我觉得他带点口音
No. I-I think he had an accent.
那可能是欧洲人了
So European, maybe.
我去国际刑事警察组织检索他的照片
I'll run his photo through interpol, see if they know him.
我会派警员去排查视频是在哪拍摄的
And I'll have unis canvass where that video was taken
看看周围有没有人见过他
and see if anyone in that neighborhood recognizes him.
谢了两位  我们还能做什么
Thanks, guys. Okay, what else can we do?
卡塞尔  你不能继续参与了
Castle, you can't be a part of this. Not anymore.
你说什么呀  我必须参与
What do you mean? I have to be.
我们并不知道这个人要干什么
We don't know this man's agenda.
不  贝克特  我需要
No, no, Beckett. I need to be --
你需要回家
What you need to do is go back to the loft
好好待着
and stay there.
我已经派了警员保护你
Now, I've assigned a security detail to you.
我为什么会是目标
Why would I be a target?
我不知道  你也不知道
I don't know. And neither do you.
但在泰国时他就想杀你
But he was shooting at you in Thailand.
而他刚刚杀了杰夫·鲍尔斯
And he just killed Jeff Powers,
你所谓的查克·诺里斯
your Chuck Norris look-alike.
警员会送你回家
Now, L.T. is gonna drive you home.
我要是拒绝呢
And if I refuse?
那就铐起来然后送你回家
Then he'll drive you home in handcuffs.
我要说清楚  我郁闷
Just for the record? Extremely bitter.
我们找到了什么会告诉你的
I'll call you if we find anything.
蕾妮  你有什么发现
Lanie, hey. What did you find?
首先  鲍尔斯先生的血检结果出来了
Well, for one thing, Mr. Powers' blood work came back.
他体内也有登革热抗体
He had antibodies for dengue fever.
跟卡塞尔一样
Just like Castle.
菌株很相似
Similar strain, too.
但最重要的发现是在他嘴里
But the main attraction is what I found in the man's mouth.
或者说  最重要的缺失
Huh. Rather, what you didn't find.
他的牙怎么了
What happened to his teeth?
被拔掉了  八颗
They were pried out -- eight of them --
发生在他死前不久
Shortly before he died.
鲍尔斯死前被拷问过  是复仇吗
So Powers was tortured first. Revenge?
或者是凶手想知道什么信息
Or the killer wanted information.
留下了什么线索吗
Did he leave any evidence behind?
恐怕没有
I'm afraid not.
他应该是戴着医用手套
Looks like he wore latex gloves.
我在被害人的口腔里发现了滑石粉的痕迹
I found traces of talc in the victim's mouth.
那手套上一定有血迹
The gloves would have been bloody.
凶手肯定得扔掉它们
The killer would have to get rid of them.
上面也许就有凶手的指纹或者DNA
They could have his prints or DNA on them.
没错  但手套根本无从找起
Right, but those gloves could be anywhere.
我们怎么找呢
How would we find them?
局里有警犬
The department has bloodhounds.
联系警犬小队  让他们带上警犬
Call the K-9 unit, have them deploy bloodhounds
搜查鲍尔斯的公寓周边
to search near Powers' apartment building.
谢谢
Thanks.
找到手套了吗
Find the gloves yet?
目前还一无所获
Oh, nothing so far.
我这边也是
Yeah, not with my team either.
也许警犬能有什么发现呢
Well, the dogs may still come through.
我觉得可能性不大
I'm not so sure.
说不定
For all we know,
凶手根本就没有丢掉手套
the killer didn't even toss his gloves.
怎么  就带着血迹斑斑的手套上街吗
So what? He's just walking around with bloody latex?
不  他可以装在密封袋里带走
Nah. He could have put them in a ziploc bag,
或者是烧掉
could have burned them.
重点在于  就算真找到了手套
Yeah, the thing of it is, even if we find the gloves
取得了凶手的指纹DNA  确认了身份
and get the killer's prints or dna and we do I.D. this guy,
他恐怕也早逃之夭夭了
he's probably long gone by now.
-为什么  -如果他想要的是信息
- Based on what? - Well, if he wanted information,
很可能已经在对杰夫·鲍尔斯的
he probably got it from Jeff Powers,
拷问中得到了
yanking out all of his teeth.
不  鲍尔斯这样训练有素的士兵
No. A soldier like Powers? His training?
他是死也不会招的
No, he'd die before he spilled his guts.
我希望你说错了
I hope you're wrong about that.
因为如果凶手要的是信息
'cause if our killer was after information,
他可能会认为卡塞尔知道
he may think Castle has it.
你不是说今晚要在朋友家住吗
Hey. I thought you said you were staying at a friend's tonight.
不  是你说要我去朋友家住的
No. Uh, you said I was staying at a friend's.
是吗  那你怎么不听话呢
Oh. Well, then, you should have listened.
我想陪着你
I wanted to be here with you.
我知道这案子对你意义重大
I know this isn't just another case.
那个  昨天在我办公室
Oh, yeah. Listen -- yesterday morning in my office.
我简直跟《回到未来》的布朗博士似的
I know I was a little Doc Brown, "Back to the future."
在泰国到底发生了什么事  爸爸
What really went on in Thailand, dad?
我知道你肯定有猜测了
I know you must have a theory.
那还用说  有一大堆
Uh, believe me, I have dozens.
哪个最吓人
Which one scares you the most?
我不需要你保护我
I don't need you to protect me.
我不再是个小孩子了
I'm not a kid anymore.
我也不害怕听到真相了
I'm not afraid to hear the truth.
没错  你不怕了  对吧
That's right. You aren't, are you?
为什么不让我参与进来
Why not let me in?
我想忘记一切
I wanted to forget everything.
在最黑暗的时刻  我一直在想...
So in my darkest moments, I wonder if I...
我是不是做了什么糟糕的事情
Did something terrible.
我了解你
I know you.
你永远不会做坏事的
You would never do anything bad.
我永远不会离开我的挚爱
I could never leave the love of my life,
抛下她和你整整两个月
desert her and you for two months.
可不知怎的我还是做了
And somehow I did.
卡塞尔
Castle.
我们怎么找到这家伙的
How did we I.D. this guy?
是一条名叫库丘的警犬找到的
By way of a bloodhound named Cujo.
库丘在一个离案发现场四个街区远的
Cujo sniffed out a paper bag in a storm drain
下水道里发现了一个纸袋
about four blocks away from the crime scene.
袋子里有乳胶手套
The bag contained latex gloves.
我们能确认这幅手套是凶手的
And we're sure these gloves belong to the killer?
是的  袋子里还有牙齿
Yeah. The bag had teeth in it, too.
无论如何  鉴证科都找到了指纹
In any case, CSU was able to pull prints.
我们在ECRIS找到匹配  那是欧洲指纹网络
We got a hit off ECRIS, European fingerprint network.
那凶手是欧洲人
So the killer's European?
他是俄国人  叫伊利亚·戈洛夫金
He's Russian. Ilya Golovkin.
凯赛尔  这个名字听着耳熟吗
Castle, does that name sound familiar?
不  他是谁
No. Who is he?
他曾在雪域特战队服役过...
He served in Spetsnaz --
俄国的特种部队...
Russian special forces --
然后加入了克格勃
then moved on to the former KGB.
俄国人是幕后黑手
The Russians are behind this?
不太可能
Mm, doubtful.
他五年前离开俄罗斯  消失了
He left Russia five years ago and disappeared.
从那之后  传言称他是
Since then, word is that he's been responsible
数十起暗杀事件的凶手
for over two dozen assassinations.
包括政客  异见记者
Including politicians, dissident journalists,
受保护证人  甚至还有个梵蒂冈银行家
protected witnesses, even a Vatican banker.
有别人完成不了的事
Golovkin's the guy you call
你就可以联系戈洛夫金
when you have a job that no one else can do.
卡塞尔  如果戈洛夫金也牵涉其中
Castle, if Golovkin is involved,
那不论是怎么回事
then whatever's going on,
不论你参与了什么  肯定是个大事情
whatever you were a part of, it's something big.
给你
Here you go.
你们如何追查像戈洛夫金这样的人
How do we even track down a guy like Golovkin?
我们找了支援
We called in reinforcements.
我们和联调局协作
We're coordinating with the FBI.
每个州还有联邦执法机构
Every state and federal law-enforcement agency
都在找这个人
is looking for this guy.
等我们找到他了  你就会得到你的答案
And when we find him, you will have your answers.
他是唯一一个知道真相的人
He's the only person who knows the truth.
至少还有另外一个人也知道真相
There's at least one other person who knows.
我得看看鲍尔斯的档案
I need to see Powers' file.
第一比尔森银行
信用卡
你究竟是要找什么
Exactly what are you hoping to find?
我们已经翻遍了关于鲍尔斯为数不多的资料
We already went over what little there is on Powers.
是的  可你们要找的是凶手
Yes, but you were looking for his killer.
我要找的是这家伙
I'm looking for this guy.
詹金斯是这一切的幕后操纵者
Jenkins is the mastermind behind this,
不然就是幕后指使的副手
or mastermind-adjacent.
他说不定也去过泰国
He was probably in Thailand.
据我所知  他肯定在开那辆我坐的卡车
For all I know, he was driving the truck I was in.
卡塞尔  我们永远也找不到詹金斯
Castle, we could never locate Jenkins,
更不用说知道他的真名了
Much less find his real name.
说不定现在可以了呢
But maybe now we can.
如果詹金斯曾联系过鲍尔斯
If Jenkins had contact with Powers,
也许这里会有能让我们找到他的线索
There may be evidence in here that can lead us to him.
之前发的全境通缉有线索了
Yo. We got a hit off that A.P.B.
一名交警认为他看到了戈洛夫金
A transit cop thinks he just saw Golovkin get off
在谢里丹广场地铁站下来了
a subway stop at Sheridan Square.
那离杰夫·鲍尔斯的公寓只有半个街区
That's half a block from Jeff Powers' apartment.
是的  说不定他又回去了
Yeah. Maybe he went back there.
卡塞尔  待着别走  好吗
Castle, stay put, okay?
-好的  你也小心点  -我会的
- Yeah. You be careful. - I will.
我有紧急应变小组呢
ESU's got my back.
封条被人打开了  有人进去过了
The seal is cut. Someone went inside.
他说不定还在里面
He might still be there.
好  进去
Okay, go.
警察  纽约警局  纽约警局
Police! NYPD! NYPD!
探长  这里
Detectives, over here.
这是安珀  那个脱衣舞女郎
That's Amber, the stripper.
戈洛夫金肯定拷问过她了
Golovkin must have questioned her.
现在他肯定知道我们在追查他了
Now he knows we're onto him.
他带她到这里来
Bringing her here was his way
是想侮辱我们
of rubbing our faces in it.
是的  可他到底想怎样
Yeah, but what's his angle?
他究竟在找什么
What's he after?
我不知道  可不论是什么
I don't know, but whatever it is,
他肯定不会就此善罢甘休
he's not gonna stop until he gets it.
晚上好  先生  有什么可以效劳的吗
Good evening, sir. How may I help you?
其实  我是纽约警局的
Actually, I'm working with the NYPD.
我想  是否可以问你几个问题
I was wondering if I could ask you a few questions.
你见过这个人
Have you ever seen this man?
杰夫先生...当然
Mr. Jeff -- of course.
他是苏尼尔餐厅的常客
He's a regular customer here at Sunil's Caf?
绝对常客
Very regular.
事实上  过去的六个月中
In fact, for the past six months,
他每周二傍晚六点都会来这  风雨无阻
he's come here, without fail, every tuesday at 6:00 PM.
他是来这里约见什么人的吗
Was he meeting anyone?
不  他总是一个人吃饭
No. He always dines alone.
那这个人呢
What about this man?
你有没有见过他
Have you ever seen him
或者见到这两个人在一起
or the two of them together?
没有  我对这个人没有印象
No. He's not familiar to me.
-非常抱歉  -没事
- I'm sorry. - Of course.
非常感谢
Thank you for your time.
你是谁
Who are you?
你不应该来这里的
You should never have come.
如果你都找到这了  那我就是个死人了
If you're here, it means that I'm a dead man.
我以为你已经死了呢
I thought you already were a dead man.
你哪儿也不许去
You're not going anywhere
你得先告诉我这一切究竟是怎么回事
until you tell me what the hell's going on.
好吧
Fine.
我们现在就得走  马上
We must leave. Now.
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
这是什么地方
What is this place?
他们向我保证过你不会想起来的
They promised me you wouldn't remember.
你是怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
杰夫·鲍尔斯
Jeff Powers.
鲍尔斯永远不会开口的  除非...
Powers would never talk. Unless...
他已经死了  是不是
He's dead, isn't he?
什么时候
When?
-昨天  -是那个俄国人干的
- Yesterday. - Was it the Russian?
你也知道那个俄国人  怎么会
You know about the Russian? How?
这比我想的还要糟糕
This is even worse than I thought.
你在给谁打电话
Who are you calling?
这是伊卡洛斯  我这有个791状况
This is Icarus. I've got a code 7-9-1.
那是什么意思  快告诉我你是谁
What does that mean? Just tell me who you are.
我叫比拉
I'm Bilal.
比拉·汉
Bilal Khan.
我不认识我
You really don't know me.
我记得你也在那卡车里  受伤了
I know you were in the truck, wounded.
在那之前很久  我是你的朋友
Long before that, I was your friend.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
十一年级时我是菲克罗夫特预科学校的交换生
I was an exchange student at Faircroft Prp in 11th grade.
你不是  不然我会记得的
You weren't. I'd remember that.
你早就不记得了
Not anymore.
看见没
You see?
我们两个  一起
The two of us, together.
过去的美好时光
The good old days.
这是那个奖杯...
That's the trophy --
我以为我是和菲尔·巴莱特一起得的奖
The one I thought I won with Phil Bartlett.
因为他们必须把你有关我的记忆都抹去
That's because they had to erase all your memories of me
然后换成别人的
and replace them with somebody else.
他们是谁
Who are "they"?
真不敢相信他们挑了菲尔·巴莱特
I can't believe they picked Phil Bartlett.
那个蠢货
W-what a douchebag.
听着  比拉...是叫比拉  对吧
Listen, Bilal -- I-it's Bilal, right?
即使你说的都是真的
Even if what you said is true
我们在11年级时就认识
and we know each other in 11th grade --
你写第一本德里克·斯道姆小说时
You even consulted with me
甚至向我咨询过
when you wrote your first, uh, Derrick Storm book.
咨询什么了
Consulted about what?
恐怖主义
Terrorism.
鉴于我跟巴基斯坦情报部门合作紧密
Since I was working with, uh, pakistani intelligence,
我在这方面是专家
I was something of an expert on the topic.
但这些又如何解释杰夫·鲍尔斯呢
Okay, but how does that explain Jeff Powers?
他为什么每个周二都去餐馆
Why would he come to the restaurant every Tuesday?
查看我的情况
To check in with me.
他是我的指挥官  我在中情局的指挥官
He was my handler, my C.I.A. handler.
现在我的身份暴露
And now my cover's blown.
你的身份  你是间谍
Your cover? So you're a spy?
不是
Not a spy.
在我离开情报部门后
Look, after I left the intelligence service,
我失去了方向
I lost my way.
加入了基地组织
I joined Al-qaeda.
你加入了基地组织
You were in Al-qaeda?
你能小声点吗
Can you please keep your voice down?
是的
Yes, I was.
我成为他们高层领导的一员
I rose up to become a part of their senior leadership.
而你现在当服务员  住在美国
And now you're bussing tables and you live here?
这是我的选择  我的苦修
I chose this life. It's my penance.
我想离开基地组织
I wanted to leave Al-qaeda,
我手握组织的内部情报
and I had inside knowledge about that organization.
于是我跟美国情报部门达成协议
So I struck a deal with American intelligence
用我所知换来第二次机会
to trade what I knew for a second chance.
你叛变了
You defected.
如果你喜欢这种说法
If you like.
我躲在泰国的一个佛寺
I hid in a buddhist monastery in Thailand
在那我本应该与中情局联络人碰面
where I was supposed to meet my C.I.A. contact
拿到去美国的安全通行证
and get safe passage to the United States.
但事情出了岔子
But things didn't go as planned.
这跟我有什么关系  我为什么也在
And what does any of this have to do with me? Why was I there?
因为我需要你
Because I needed you.
需要我  需要我干什么
Needed me? Needed me for what?
当我准备把自己交到中情局手里时
I was about to turn myself over to the C.I.A.
我的联络人被杀
when my contact was killed
那颗子弹本来是冲我射出的
by a bullet that was meant for me.
碰头地点本应该是保密的
Now, the rendezvous point was supposed to be a secret.
也就说信息外露
Which means there was a leak.
我谁都不能相信
I could trust no one.
我手里有情报  于是同意再次碰头
I-I had some leverage, so I agreed to meet again,
但必须有我信任的人陪同
but only in the company of somebody I trusted,
我认识的人
somebody I knew.
某个很出名没法被暗杀的人
Somebody too prominent to be eliminated.
我只认识一个这样的人  你
I knew only one such man -- you.
我们怎么跑到卡车里的
How did we end up in that truck?
基地组织雇佣俄国佬追杀我
The Russian had been hunting me, hired by Al-qaeda.
他终于找上了我
He finally caught up with me.
你就是那样受伤的
That's how you got wounded.
-我也受伤了吗  -很庆幸  没有
- Was I wounded, too? - Fortunately, no.
车来了
My ride's here.
我还有很多问题
I still have a lot of questions.
没时间了  抱歉  里克
There's no more time. I-I'm sorry, Rick.
是我给你的生活制造了种种麻烦
Look, I was the cause of much upheaval in your life.
希望你能知道那不是我的本意
Please know that was never my intention.
事实上  我对你所做一切
In fact, I have the deepest gratitude
感激涕零
for everything that you've done.
真希望我能记得我做了什么
I just wish I could remember what it was.
我也希望如此
As do I.
估计我们不会再见面了
I doubt we'll meet again.
祝好
Be well.
走到暗处
Come away from the light.
快
Come.
听着  我跟这一切无关
Look, I'm -- I'm... i'm not part of this.
我什么都不知道
I know absolutely nothing.
那不重要
It does not matter.
我以为我们说好的
I thought we had an understanding
你不会追查此事
that you wouldn't pursue this.
詹金斯
Jenkins.
你得忘记比拉·汉
Well, you'll have to forget about Bilal Khan
和今天发生的一切
and everything else that's occurred tonight.
你要帮我忘记吗
Are you gonna help me to forget?
最好不要
We'd prefer not to.
那谢谢你了
Yes, well... thank you for that.
还有...
Oh, and, uh...
这一拳是为了错过我的婚礼
That's for making me miss my wedding day.
你不知道你有多幸运  卡塞尔先生
You have no idea how lucky you are, Mr. Castle.
至于错过婚礼  那是不可避免的
As for missing your wedding, that was unavoidable,
-如果这能让你有些慰藉  -不能
- If it's any consolation. - It's not.
你拽着我转了大半个地球
You dragged me halfway across the world.
你欠我个解释
You owe me an explanation.
我不能告诉你
I'm not at liberty to give you one.
那我也不能忘记比拉·汉
Well, then I'm not at liberty to forget about Bilal Khan.
或是戈洛夫金
Or Golovkin here.
-卡塞尔先生  -怎么
- Mr. Castle -- - What?
你要杀我吗  你杀不了
You gonna kill me? You can't.
会引发太多疑问
Raise too many questions.
所以你把我从泰国带回来
That's why you brought me back from Thailand,
洗去我的记忆
Minus my memory.
我失踪两个月  都是因为你
I was gone two months thanks to you.
我错过了我的婚礼
I missed my wedding.
是什么事  就不能再等一天
What couldn't wait one more day?
时间紧迫
There was a ticking clock.
我们听闻
We'd picked up chatter
基地组织要袭击美国
about a major Al-qaeda strike in the U.S.
我们知道袭击几小时内就要进行  没时间
We knew it was hours away and there was never enough time
搜集线索  阻止他们
for us to put the pieces together in order to stop it.
但比拉知道袭击的事
But Bilal knew about the strike.
人名  地点  行动细节
Names, places, operational details, yeah.
我们迫切需要比拉和他的情报
We were desperate for Bilal and his intel.
他的联络人被杀后
And when his contact was killed,
我们需要你来得到比拉
we needed you to get Bilal.
他交代了一切
And he came through.
我们得以阻止袭击
We were able to prevent the strike,
将参与的人全部除掉
and we neutralized everyone involved.
我只能说这么多
That's all I can tell you.
希望你不要对别人重复
And I expect you not to repeat it.
这么想  的确  你错过了婚礼
Think of it this way -- yeah, you missed your wedding,
但你解救了成百上千人的性命
but you also saved tens of thousands of lives.
你该走了  卡塞尔先生
You should leave now, Mr. Castle.
你解救了成百上千人的性命
You saved tens of thousands of lives?
去泰国执行秘密任务
And went on a secret mission to Thailand?
是的  但我不能透露更多
Yes. Unfortunately, I cannot divulge any further specifics.
告诉我们  就得杀了我们
If you told us, you'd have to kill us.
贫嘴  都是为了你们的安全
You mock, but it is for your own safety.
重要的是
I guess what really matters is,
你知道了真相  老爸  好消息是
you found out the truth, dad, and the good news is,
不是什么很糟的事情
it didn't turn out to be your worse-case scenario.
坏消息是
Yeah, bad news is,
我没法把英雄壮举到处吹嘘
I can't brag about my heroic exploits to anyone.
现在不就在吹嘘
Though you're kind of doing that right now.
完全是
Totally.
-我去学习了  -拜拜
- I have to go study. - See you.
亲爱的  阿莱克西斯和我
You know, darling, Alexis and I
不需要知道细节
do not need to know the details.
但我希望你能告诉凯瑟琳
But I do hope you can tell Katherine.
当然
Of course.
我尽快赶回来
I got here as soon as I could.
不够快
Never soon enough.
你没事我很开心
I'm just glad that you're okay.
别告诉阿莱克西斯和老妈
Um, don't tell Alexis or mother
俄罗斯杀手的事
about the Russian-assassin part.
那部分我略过了
I left that out of the story.
小巷里发生的事
Yeah, well, um, there's no proof
无凭无证
of what happened in that alley.
等警员赶到时  尸体已经不见了
By the time uniforms got there, his body was already gone.
如果詹金斯能抹去记忆
If Jenkins can get rid of memories,
处理尸体小菜一碟
getting rid of a body would be child's play.
我很抱歉  凯特
I am so sorry, Kate,
为那些我令你经历的事
for everything I put you through.
宝贝  你又不是在泰国开派对
Babe, it's not like you were partying in Thailand.
错过婚礼  你有最好的借口
You have the best excuse ever for missing our wedding.
你在拯救世界
You were saving the world.
是啊  但还是有很多未回答的问题
Yeah. Still a lot of unanswered questions, though.
我是怎么中枪的  怎么失踪两个月的
Like how did I get shot? Why was I gone for two months?
是啊  你或许不知道全部真相
Yeah. You may not know everything.
是的  不过知道的够多了
No. But I know enough.
为这干杯
Let's drink to that.